## RELAND BOYLE

# **Software Engineer**

631-806-0019 • reland.boyle@gmail.com • New York, NY • linkedin.com/in/relandboyle • github.com/relandboyle

#### SUMMARY

Software engineer and generalist with 15+ years of professional experience in product development, mechanical design, project management, vendor relations, compliance, and customer success. Known for rapidly becoming a subject-matter expert and trusted source for information and wisdom. Highly attuned to the needs of the customer, the organization, the team, and the product.

#### **SKILLS**

JavaScript • TypeScript • Dart • Python • Angular • React • Flutter • Flask • RxJS • Node • Express • Docker • Kubernetes • SQL/NoSQL • Material UI • Angular Material • Flutter Material • CSS/Sass/Less • Electron • AWS • Linode • Linux • Python • OAuth • Auth0 • D3 • Grafana • Prometheus • Git/GitHub • BitBucket • Travis CI • Google Cloud •

# **Work Experience**

#### Citigroup - Senior Software Engineer, Frontend

May 2022 - Present

- Developed reusable Angular components, modules, and services for Citi applications across more than five internal departments
- Conducted behavioral and technical interviews and provided feedback to candidates for Citi's C12 and C13 engineering roles
- Implemented "Angular Office Hours" to decrease the onboarding duration for new-hire Angular engineers by approximately 50%
- Built a library of 30+ custom Flutter widgets with Material themes consistent with Citi brand elements and design principles

#### DataCaliper - NetSuite Developer

November 2021 - March 2022

- Integrated SuiteScript 2.0 programs within SuiteCloud Developer Framework to customize NetSuite instances for 5+ clients
- Produced Advanced PDF Templates, Workflows, and Formula Fields to reduce wait times and cognitive load by up to 60%
- Typically responded to client requests within 24 hours with effective, creative solutions and delivered within 5 business days

### Rich Brilliant Willing - Assistant Director of Operations

January 2016 - August 2021

- Optimized processes across departments, automating repetitive tasks and implementing integrations between Oracle NetSuite ERP/CRM and 4 secondary platforms, working with tech such as NetSuite Workflows and SuiteScript Developer Framework
- Achieved 100% product compliance with relevant consumer product safety standards and internal performance standards
- Founded and managed RBW's Customer Success Team, hired CSR's, established metrics and service level agreements, reduced post-sale support cases from 15% to 5% of all sales while mentoring team members and generating internal tech wiki
- Routinely directed \$1M+ custom lighting projects through ideation, design, validation, manufacturing, delivery, and installation

### **Recent Projects**

#### <u>Drone Tools React</u> / <u>Drone Tools Angular</u>

November 2022

- Developed a single-page React/TypeScript application for drone pilots to calculate propeller tip speed relative to local Mach 1
   Developed a single-page React/TypeScript application for drone pilots to calculate propeller tip speed relative to local Mach 1
- Rebuilt the application in Angular using reactive forms, RxJS Observables, Behavior Subjects, and Angular Material dialogs
- Employed Netlify/AWS Lambda serverless functions to mask sensitive data in API calls from a frontend-only web application
- Introduced SCSS style sheets to achieve a responsive, mobile-friendly design that renders gracefully on screens of all sizes

Skills Grid

February 2022

- Constructed a full-stack JavaScript web app with CRUD functionality using DOM manipulation, Express, and plain vanilla JS
- Authored modular LESS style sheets to provide consistent styling and transitions while writing more readable, maintainable CSS
- Realized an idea put forth by Codesmith Chief Academic Officer Phillip Troutman to aid new graduates in their first job search

**KR8S for Kubernetes** 

November 2021

- Created a React/Electron single-page desktop application under the OS Labs Beta tech accelerator to visualize and monitor Kubernetes cluster health and performance metrics, providing developers with real-time insight into the impact of changes made to the deployed application, streamlining development and reducing the need to review and respond to logs by up to 75%
- Automated deployment of a Dockerized multi-service React-based e-commerce application in a local Kubernetes cluster with a
  pre-configured Prometheus server and over 10 Grafana dashboards for a 50% reduction in setup time for new Kubernetes users

### **EDUCATION**

Triplebyte Engineering - <u>Certificate</u>

January 2023

Codesmith - Advanced Residency for Software Engineers - Syllabus

November 2021 June 2020

Dassault Systemes - Certified SolidWork - <u>Certificate</u>

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Codesmith Career Support Engineer

February 2022 - present

Tech Talks - Sponsored by Single Sprout: <u>User Experience Best Practices</u>

October 2021

Rich Brilliant Willing - Help Center

August 2021